Guide to the Ford Madox Ford collection, [ca. 1850]-1973
Ford, Ford Madox collection,
- Series II. Outgoing correspondence
  - Q-Z
    - TL[copy] to W.H.D. Rouse, Jul.13, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 15)
      [Olivet] Dear Mr. Rouse: I am indeed flattered that you should have sent me your Iliad, and by the nice things you say
    - TL[copy] to Rowohlt Verlag, [1937?]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 16)
      Clarkesville, TN; Dear Sirs: Messrs. Houghton Mifflin have forwarded me your letter of the twenty-first of April
    - TL[copy] to William E. Rudge, Feb.18, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 17)
      New York; My dear Mr. Rudge: I have not myself got a copy of the letter you wrote Bradley
    - TL[copy] to William E. Rudge, Feb.20, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 18)
      [New York] Dear Mr. Rudge: Here is the manuscript of "New York Essays". Will you please let Miss Gordon, the bearer, have a receipt for it,
    - TL[copy] to Leah Salisbury, May 15, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 19)
      Toulon; Dear Madam: Mr. Young suggested that I might put the einema right of my book, THE RASH ACT in your hands
    - TL[copy] to the Editor, The Saturday Review, Nov.23, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 20)
      New York; Dear Sir, Two years ago today Dr Canby commissioned from me an article on wine
    - TL[copy] to Isidor Schneider, Sept.14, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 21)
      Paris; My dear Schneider, I see no reason inprinciple why I should not write for the PHILADELPHIA INQUIRER
    - TL[copy] to Isidore Schneider, Oct.1, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 22)
      [Paris] Dear Mr. Schneider, I have already forwarded to you personally a number of sufficiently eccentric snapshots of myself
    - TL[draft] to R.A. Scott-James, [Sept, 1907?]; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 23)
      Hythe; Dear Mr. James: Thank you for yr. letter: the exact circumstances were these: I was helping Marshall
    - TL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, [Jan., 1910]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 24)
      London; My dear James, Thanks. You have written a very nice letter and I am grateful to you.
    - TL[copy]S to R.A. Scott-James, [Jan., 1910?]; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 25)
      London; Dear James, I am sorry you appear to feel yourself aggrieved. Of course I should not have ordered an article from you
    - TL[copy]S to R.A. Scott-James, Jun.30, 1911; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 26)
      London; Dear James/ I've cut this blessed thing with coolness and ferocity. But I really can't judge of lengths a bit
    - TL[copy]S to R.A. Scott-James, May 11, 1911; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 27)
      Giessen; My dear James, Of course I am going to write the articles for you. But I have been busy and lazy
    - TL[copy]S to R.A. Scott-James, [Jan., 1914?]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 28)
      Selsey; My dear Scottie, I suppose I may now congratulate you, as I do very heartily at having again got your foot into
    - TL[copy]S to R.A. Scott-James, Feb.3, 1925; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 29)
      Guermantes; My dear Scott-James, Your letter dated 4th Sep and announcing your intention of visiting Paris on the 6th of that month has only just reached me
    - AL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, Apr.2, [1935]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 30)
      [New York] My dear Scott-James/ I was very pleased to see your signature again after so long an interval. [ Written on TLS Scott-James to Ford, March 12, 1935]
    - TL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, [Sept.29, 1935]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 31)
      [New York] Dear Scott James, I don't know if these things have been offered to you - if not, take a look at them
    - TL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, Oct.28, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 32)
      [Paris] Dear James, Send me the cheque for that article, will you? Things are so bad here that one really needs to keep all the money by one
    - TL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, Nov.10, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 33)
      Paris; My dear Scott James, I am sending you under this cover some poems by my friend Mrs Michael Lake
    - TL[draft] to R.A. Scott-James, Jan.19, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 34)
      [New York] My dear Scott-James: It was nice to see your signature again. (Would you get your mail clerk to observe
    - TL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, Jan.19, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 35)
      New York; My dear Scott James: It was nice to see your signature again. (Would you get your mail clerk to observe
    - TL[draft] to R.A. Scott-James, Jan.27, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 36)
      [New York] My dear Scott-James: Here is a short story that I have written with the Mercury in view,
    - TL[copy] to R.A. Scott-James, Jan.27, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 37)
      My dear Scott-James: Here is a short story that I have written with the Mercury in view
    - AL[copy,fragment] to George Bernard Shaw, Nov.25, 1908; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 38)
      London; ... With regard to the National Theatre, I offered at the first meeting of the Committee which I attended
    - TL[copy] to Horace Shipp, Mar.11, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 39)
      Paris; Dear Sir, I have now received the proofs of your short stories and will let you have a note about them early next week.
    - TL[copy] to Horace Shipp, Mar.29, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 40)
      Toulon; Dear Mr. Shipp, Here is the note about the English Review. I am so sorry to have kept you waiting
    - TL[copy] to Horace Shipp, Apr.10, 1932; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 41)
      Toulon; Dear Mr. Shipp, Mr. Ford would like very much toknow if you have received the note
    - TL[copy] to Horace Shipp, Aug.25, 1933; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 42)
      [Toulon] Dear Mr. Shipp, I am of course much touched by your wanting to dedicate your new venture to me
    - TL[copy] to George Shively, Apr.21, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 43)
      [Greensboro?] Dear Mr. Shively: Your letter to Dahlberg is admirable and ought to be most helpful.
    - TL[copy] to Harrison Smith, Nov.1, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 44)
      New York; My dear Mr. Smith: Mr. Ford Madox Ford has asked me to send you the enclosed synopsis of the book[Typed by Carolyn Gordon]
    - TL[copy] to Harrison Smith, May 5, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 45)
      [Paris] Dear Harold: I expect to finish my novel in the course of the coming week and purpose to send a copy for England to you,
    - TL[copy] to Harrison Smith, Mar.19, 1935; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 46)
      [New York?] My dear Harrison Smith, I have considewred that project and I don't see, very regretfully, that I can go on with it.
    - TL[copy] to Harrison Smith, May 10, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 47)
      New York; My dear Harrison Smith: I enclose herewith the amended letter about FINNEGANS WAKE.
    - TL[copy] to Harrison Smith, May 10, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 48)
      New York; My dear Harrison Smith: I am quite ready to write the six articles for the Saturday Review for which you have asked
    - TL[copy] to Harrison Smith, Apr.14, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 49)
      [New York?] My dear Smith: I shall be starting my first article for you almost immediately, and you ought to have it in a day or two.
    - TL[copy] to Janet Adam Smith, Jun.3, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 50)
      [Toulon] Dear Madam, I am flattered and obliged by your letter of the 17th ult. which has followed me about a good deal.
    - TL[copy] to Janet Adam Smith, Jul.8, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 51)
      Toulon; Dear Madam, I see before me shortly a few days in which I could write that Article about the American Literary Scene,
    - TL[copy] to Janet Adam Smith, Jul.28, 1934; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 52)
      Toulon; Dear Madam, I enclose herewith the AMERICAN SCENE. I HOPE IT IS Not too long or too late
    - TL[copy] to L. Tinlden Smith, [Mar., 1929?]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 53)
      [Paris?] Dear Sirs, Yours of the 18th ult/ Mr Ford asks me to reply to this as follows: Mr Ford was asked by Mr. Covici to make a translation [Signed by Secretary]
    - TL[copy] to L. Tilden Smith, May 5, 1929; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 54)
      [Paris?] Re. Miss Rhys' translation of "Perversite"/ Dear Sir: In reference yours of the 11th of April. I wish to tnak you for the above
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, [1931?]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 55)
      [Toulon?Paris?] Dear T.R. Smith, I have to thank you for your letter of the 6th inst. I am glad you like the Reminiscences
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Feb.2, 1931; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 56)
      My deear T.R. Smith: WHEN THE WICKED MAN/ On a separate sheet inclosed herewith I send [ing] some directions for whoever looks after your proofs
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Mar.2, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 57)
      [Toulon] My dear T.R. Smith, There seems to be considerable of a muddle about WHEN THE WICKED MAN's proofs.
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Mar.14, 1931; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 58)
      [Toulon?] My dear T.R. Smith: What has happened to WHEN THE WICKED MAN? I am so mazed by the various cables that I dont know when to expect its publication.
    - AL[fragment] to T.R. Smith, Mar.20, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 59)
      Toulon; My dear T.R. Smith/ Your letter of March 5th received yesterday reduced ne to a state of blithering idiocy.
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Apr.17, 1931; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 60)
      Toulon; Dear T.R. Smith, You still quite misunderstand the Viking matter. I presume you have not seen the release of the book
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, May 18, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 61)
      [Topulon] Dear T.R. Smith: Your cable was delayed in reaching me owing to its insufficient address.
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Jul.4, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 62)
      Toulon; Dear T.R. Smith, I mailed the ms of my reminiscences to Miss Kerr today. It runs to about 120,000 words
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Jul27, 1931; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 63)
      Toulon; Dear T.R. Smith, I regret that you do not like my reminiscences. You might have looked at the matter in a different light
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Sept.24, 1931; 3 leaves (Box 41, Folder 64)
      [Toulon] Dear T.R. Smith, The proofs, the sending of which you annouce to me in your letter of the 11th inst; which reached me on the 20th,
    - TL[copy] to T.R. Smith, Oct.17, 1931; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 65)
      [Toulon] Dear T.R. Smith/ I received the remainder of the proofs of RETURN TO YESTERDAY on the 12th inst.
    - AL[copy] to David Soskice, Jun.8, 1909; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 66)
      [N.p.] Dear David/ There has been no weakness or indecision on my part but I think you have misunderstood the position.
    - TL[copy] to Arthur B. Spingarn, Jun.2, 1927; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 67)
      Paris; Dear Mr Spingarn/ Owing to the dilatory habits of Messrs Albert & Charles Boni I have decided to transfer my books from them
    - ALS to Jean Stafford, Feb.14, [1938?]; 1 leaf + envelope (Box 41, Folder 68)
      Paris; Dear Miss Stafford: I am rather worn out after a long illness: but I will certainly write you a strong recommendation
    - TLS to Jean Stafford, Apr.26, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 69)
      New York; Dear Jean: I will read the stories almost immediately. What do you want me to do after I've read them?
    - TL[copy], Apr.26, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 70)
    - ALS to Jean Stafford, May 30, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 71)
      New York; These are swell! I will write about them for the Normandie
    - TL[copy] to Gertrude Stein, Sept.18, 1924; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 72)
      Paris; Dear Miss Stein, I have just got your letter of the fifteenth. I am very sorry that you have had to wait for your cheque.
    - TL[copy] to Gertrude Stein, Sept.8, [1928]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 73)
      Carqueiranne; My dear Gertrude, How nice to hear from you. I have been playing hermit and incidentally working rather hard here for a month or so past [dated incorrectly 1931]
    - TL[copy] to Gertrude Stein, Dec.25, 1928; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 74)
      Paris; Dear Gertrude/ I wish you'd let my friend Allen Tate who is a very fine poet call on you with his wife.
    - TL[copy] to George Stevens, May 17, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 75)
      New York; Dear Mr. Stevens: Alright. Let it go at that. I take it that the remaining articles you want are to be one more
    - TL[copy] to George Stevens, Oct.17, 1939; 1 leaf + 7 leaves (Box 41, Folder 75.5)
      [This folder contains facsimiles of 4 Ford letters and one George Stevens letter; note by Max Saunders included]
    - TL[copy] to Brett Stokes, Mar.16, 1939; 1 leaf + 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 76)
      New York; Dear Mr. Stevens: I forward you under separate sheet the aims and purposes of the TRANATLANTIC REVIEW
    - TL[copy] to Harold Strauss, May 8, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 77)
      New York; Dear Mr. Strauss: I am delighted that you should take an intereest in Miss Welty's stories.
    - TL[copy] to Allene Talmey, Jun.22, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 78)
      Calrksville, Tenn.; Dear Miss Talmey: The article which is on "The Athens of the South" is well on its way and is in fact nearly done.
    - TL[copy], Jul.5, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 79)
      [Clarksville, Tenn.?] Dear Miss Talmey; By this time you will probably have received the article, or if not, you can expect it any day.
    - Removed (Box 41, Folder 80)
    - TL[copy] to Allen Tate, Mar.13, 1939; 3 leaves (Box 41, Folder 81)
      New York; My dear Allen: My schemes for the TRANSATLANTIC REVIEW are beginning to solidify.
    - TL[copy] to Allen Tate, Mar.24, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 82)
      [New York] Dear Allen: Yes, you impressed me as being more sanguine thatn perhaps you were; still it can't be helped -
    - TL[copy] to Allen Tate, May 3, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 83)
      New York; Dear Allen: Could you let me know what has happened about the Chapel Hill project?
    - TL[copy] to Allen Tate, May 19, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 84)
      [New York] Dear Allen: Dahlberg who was the first guest of honour of the William Carlos Williams Society is looking out for some sort
    - TL[copy] to W.H. Thompson, Feb.5, 1926; 2 leaves (Box 41, Folder 85)
      [Tarascon?] Dear Mr Thompson, I am rather bothered by a matter as to which I should be glad of your advice:
    - TL[copy] to W.H. Thompson, [1928?]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 86)
      Paris; Dear Mr Thompson, Self and Duckworths/ Would you please forward as soon as is convenient a copy of my agreement
    - ALS to Yates Thompson, [1896?]; 1 leaf (Box 41, Folder 87)
      [London] Dear Sir- As it is proposed to hold a complete & comprehensive exhibition of the works of Madox Brown
    - TL[draft] to the Editor, The Times Literary Supplement, [n.d.]; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 1)
      [Paris] Dear Sir, Since yo have printed a letter from Mrs Conrad on my book "Joseph Conrad: A Personal Remembrance", I should like to be allowed to state
    - TL[copy] to Edward W. Titus, Mar.11, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 2)
      [Paris] Dear Mr. Titus, It was obliging of you to send me by Mr Putnam a message to the effect that you wanted that story.
    - TL[copy] to Edward W. Titus, Mar.11, 1930; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Paris; Dear Mr Titus, Thank you. You offered me howecer frs 2,000 for anything I would send you.
    - TL[copy] to Philip Unwin, Sept.1, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 4)
      [New York] Dar Mr Philip Unwin, Yours of the 17th ult. ref translations. I think it would be best if you would communicate with Mrs E.G. Bown about these.
    - TL[photocopy]S to Stanley Unwin, Sept.16, 1936; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Paris; Dear Mr Unwin, Before he left, yesterday, Crankshaw communicated to me your letter of the 7th inst.
    - TL[carbon copy] to Stanley Unwin, Sept.16, 1936; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Sept.26, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 7)
      [Toulon?]Dear Mr Wnwin, Your name certainly seems to have worked wonders on Mr Greenslet- for I have just had a wire from him
    - TL[carbon copy] to Stanley Unwin, Nov.3, 1936; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 8)
      [Paris]Dear Mr Unwin, We hope to leave for New York in about a week's time. I had hoped also to go by way of London,
    - TL[photocopy] to Stanley Unwin, Nov.3, 1936; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Paris; Dear Mr Unwin, We hope to leave for New York in about a week's time. I had hoped also to go by way of London,
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Nov.10, 1936; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 10)
      [Paris] Dear Mr Unwin, I am much obliged to you for your letter of November 6th. It is kind of you to give yourself so much trouble,
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jan.15, 1937; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 11)
      [New York] Dear Mr. Unwin, Greenslet of Houghton Mifflin has not yet made up his mind about the History, nor, indeed, has he even signified
    - TL[photocopy] to Stanley Unwin, [Jan.25, 1937?]; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 12)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin, Greenslet of Houghton Mifflin has not yet made up his mind about the History, nor, indeed, has he even signified
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.24, 1937; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 13)
      [New York?] Dear Mr. Unwin, Thank you for your helpful letter of the 12th inst. I am glad GREAT TRADE ROUTE seems to be doing pretty well.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.26, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 14)
      [New York] Dear Mr. Wunwin: Thanks for yours of the 19th of February. I am glad you are thinking of doing the poems.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Apr.16, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 15)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: There seems to be some muddle about the question of Translation rights. I thought I made it quite plain
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, May 29, 1937; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 16-17)
      Clarksville, Tenn.;My dear Unwin: Ref. yours of the 13th of May which has just reached me. On the 26th of February, last, I addressed you a letter [placed in 2 different folders when processed?]
    - TL[photocopy] to Stanley Unwin, May 29, 1937; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 18)
      Clarksville, Tenn.;My dear Unwin: Ref. yours of the 13th of May which has just reached me. On the 26th of February, last, I addressed you a letter
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Sept.5, 1937; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 19-20)
      Olivet; Dear Mr Unwin, After criss-crossing the whole continent from East to West, we have arrived once more here [placed in 2 different folders when processed?]
    - TL[photocopy] to Stanley Unwin, Sept.5, 1937; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 21)
      Olivet; Dear Mr. Unwin, After criss-crossing the whole continent from East to West, we have arrived once more here
    - AL[draft] to Stanley Unwin, Sept.23, [1937?]; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 22)
      [Olivet] Dear Mr. Unwin: [?] you & your firm a no.[shorthand] [Not in Ford's hand]
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.24, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 23)
      Paris; Dear Mr Unwin, I have just received MIGHTIER THAN THE SWORD. It is very handsome and I am umch pleased with it
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.25, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 24)
      [Paris?] Dear Mr Unwin, Mrs. Ford asks me to say that if your illustrators have done with her drawings for PROVENCE she would be much obliged
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.15, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 25)
      Paris; Dear Mr. Unwin, I have to thank you at once for your cehque [sic] for which I am much obliged and for your letter of the 12th inst.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.20, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 26)
      Paris; Dear Mr Unwin, One always forgets the most important things to the last: Ref. My HISTORY OF LITERATURE. This is now getting to a formidable
    - TL[copy,fragment] to Stanley Unwin, Apr.16, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 27)
      [Olivet] Extract from letter from Ford Madox Ford. I am sending, or rather I shall be sendling you as soon as we can get to some place
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jun.8, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 28)
      [Olivet] Dear Mr. Unwin: Do not bother about the lost preface. I think PROVENCE explains itself without preliminary matter
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jul.15, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 29)
      [Olivet] Dear Mr. Unwin: I finished the HISTORY OF LITERATURE with a tremendous rush on Tuesday the 12th inst.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jul.26, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 30)
      [Olivet] Dear Mr. Unwin: It was agreed in my letter of 15/3/38 and your answer to the same that I should not correct the proofs
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Aug.4, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 31)
      [Olivet] Dear Mr. Unwin; I am returning herewith the marked proof with the best answers I can make to the enigmas
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Oct.12, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 32)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: As my secretary wrote you yesterday, I have already forwarded you the final proofs
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Oct.13, 1938; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 33)
      New York; Yours of the 23rd. Dear Mr. Unwin: Thank you for the kind things you say. I was, myself, very much against the title
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Nov.14, 1938; 3 leaves (Box 42, Folder 34)
      [New York?] Dear Mr. Unwin: Yours of the 31st/ a. Ref. MARCH OF LITERATURE/ You say the proofs of the MARCH OF LITERATURE have been carefully studied
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Dec.7, 1938; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 35)
      [New York] Dear Mr. Unwin: I really do not mind what you do with the title of MARCH OF LITERATURE.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, [Dec.9, 1938]; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 36)
      New York; YOURS OF THE 25th/ Dear Mr. Unwin: I have been a long time answering the above because various matters in which
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jan.4, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 37)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: I am instructing one of my disciples, Mr. Paul Alexander Bartlett, of Arizona,
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jan.24, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 38)
      [New York] Dear Mr. Unwin: In yours of the 25th of November, last, you say "a paragraph or two at the end of the last chapters -
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jan.25, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 39)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: There are two absurd slips of the pen in "The March of Literature" that might possibly escape your proof readers:
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Jan.25, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 40)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: With regard to the translation of "La Conquete de La Vie": I am doing my best to find a publisher
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.3, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 41)
      New York; My dear Mr. Unwin: You should be receiving about this time two manuscripts whose authors I recommended to send them to you.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.16, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 42)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: I was much flattered to find myself on the frong page of your catalogue with such an extremely charming blurb.
    - TL[photocopy] to Stanley Unwin, Feb.16, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 43)
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.23, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 44)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: Additional matter for MARCH OF LITERATURE: I thought the idea of the above had been abandoned
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.23, 1939; 2 leaves (Box 42, Folder 45)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin, I have to thank you for your letter of the 3d March and as I wired you I am exceedingly obliged to you for arranging that loan.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.23, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 46)
      New York; Dear Mr. Unwin: Translation Rights: The question of the above has till now remained in rather a vague abeyance.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.29, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 47)
      New York; BOOKS RECOMMENDED/ Dear Mr. Unqin: Frederick Stokes strongly recommend three books of their spring list.
    - TL[copy] to Stanley Unwin, Mar.29, 1939; 1 leaf (Box 42, Folder 48)